William Safire Papers
William Safire Papers
- Dana Foundation files
  - Safire's files, 2001
    - Computer programs (Box 60)
    - First Ladies
      - Administrative, 3 folders (Box 60)
      - Budget (Box 60)
      - Bush, Barbara (Box 60)
      - Carter, Rosalynn (Box 60)
      - Clinton, Hillary (Box 60)
      - Clippings (Box 60)
      - Dinner, 3 folders (Box 60)
      - Draft schedules, 3 folders (Box 60)
      - Ford, Betty (Box 60)
      - Graham, Billy (Box 60)
      - Grants (Box 60)
      - Press information (Box 60)
      - Press information (Box 61)
      - Programs and press (Box 61)
      - Reagan, Nancy (Box 61)
    - Invitations (Box 61)
    - Menschel, Robert (Box 61)
    - Mittenthal, Richard (Box 61)
    - Personal, political (Box 61)
    - Reimbursement (Box 61)
    - Robert Berks sculpture (Box 61)
    - Rover, Ed -memoranda (Box 61)
    - Subscriptions (Box 61)
    - Vendor's brochures (Box 61)
- "Essay" files
  - Columns - xerox copies
    - 1973, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - 1974, 3 folders (Box 61)
    - 1975, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - 1975 (Box 62)
    - 1976, 3 folders (Box 62)
    - 1977, 4 folders (Box 62)
    - 1978, 3 folders (Box 62)
    - 1979, 3 folders (Box 62)
    - 1980 (Box 62)
    - 1980 (Box 63)
    - 1981, 4 folders (Box 63)
    - 1982, 5 folders (Box 63)
    - 1983, 3 folders (Box 63)
    - 1986 (Box 63)
    - 1986, 7 folders (Box 64)
    - 1999, 3 folders (Box 64)
    - 2000, 3 folders (Box 64)
    - 2001 (Box 64)
    - 2001 (Box 65)
    - 2002, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - 2003, 3 folders (Box 65)
    - 2004 (Box 65)
    - 2005 (Box 65)
  - Other Op-Ed columns
    - 2006, 4 folders (Box 65)
    - 2007 (Box 65)
    - 2008 (Box 65)
    - 2009 (Box 66)
    - undated (Box 66)
  - Readers' response
    - 1973 (Box 484)
    - 1974, 5 folders (Box 484)
    - 1974, 9 folders (Box 485)
    - 1975, 2 folders (Box 485)
    - 1975, 10 folders (Box 486)
    - 1975, 3 folders (Box 487)
    - 1976, 7 folders (Box 487)
    - 1976, 11 folders (Box 488)
    - 1978, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - 1979, 3 folders (Box 66)
    - 1980, 5 folders (Box 66)
    - 1981 (Box 66)
    - 1981, 5 folders (Box 67)
    - 1982, 5 folders (Box 67)
    - 1983, 3 folders (Box 68)
    - 1984 (Box 68)
    - 1985, 3 folders (Box 68)
    - 1986, 5 folders (Box 68)
    - 1986, 3 folders (Box 69)
    - 1987, 5 folders (Box 69)
    - 1988 (Box 69)
    - 1989 (Box 69)
    - 1990 (Box 69)
    - 1991 (Box 69)
    - 1992 (Box 70)
    - 1993 (Box 70)
    - 1994 (Box 70)
    - 1995 (Box 70)
    - 1996 (Box 70)
    - 1996, Hillary Clinton, 5 folders (Box 70)
    - 1996, Hillary Clinton, 8 folders (Box 71)
    - 1996, Hillary Clinton, 7 folders (Box 72)
    - 1996, Hillary Clinton, 6 folders (Box 73)
    - 1999 (Box 73)
    - 1999, 5 folders (Box 74)
    - 2000 (Box 74)
    - 2001 (Box 74)
    - 2002, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - 2003 (Box 74)
    - 2003, 10 folders (Box 75)
    - 2003, 9 folders (Box 76)
    - 2003, 9 folders (Box 77)
    - 2003, 9 folders (Box 78)
    - 2003, 9 folders (Box 79)
    - 2003, 4 folders (Box 80)
    - 2004-2006 (Box 80)
- "On Language" files
  - Administrative, Rosemary Shields
    - Correspondence, 5 folders (Box 80)
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 81)
    - Dictionary of American Regional English, 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Dictionary Society of North America (Box 81)
    - Resumes, 6 folders (Box 81)
    - Resumes, 5 folders (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 81)
  - Article index, Ann Wort
    - 1973-1978 (Box 82)
    - 1986-1993, 4 folders (Box 82)
  - Columns - xerox copies
    - 1979, 2 folders (Box 82)
    - 1980, 3 folders (Box 83)
    - 1981, 2 folders (Box 83)
    - 1982, 2 folders (Box 83)
    - 1983, 2 folders (Box 83)
    - 1984, 3 folders (Box 83)
    - 1985 (Box 83)
    - 1985, 5 folders (Box 84)
    - 1986, 7 folders (Box 84)
    - 1987, 5 folders (Box 85)
    - 1988, 4 folders (Box 85)
    - 1989 (Box 85)
    - 1990, 2 folders (Box 85)
    - 1991, 2 folders (Box 85)
    - 1992 (Box 86)
    - 1993, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1994, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1995, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1996, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1997, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1998, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 1999, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - 2000 (Box 86)
    - 2000 (Box 87)
    - 2001, 2 folders (Box 87)
    - 2002 (Box 87)
    - 2003, 2 folders (Box 87)
    - 2004, 4 folders (Box 87)
    - 2005, 4 folders (Box 87)
    - 2006, 2 folders (Box 87)
    - 2006, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - 2007, 3 folders (Box 88)
    - 2008, 3 folders (Box 88)
    - 2009, 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Lexicographic Irregulars and Readers' response
    - 1979 (Box 88)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 88)
    - 1982, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - 1983 (Box 88)
    - 1983, 2 folders (Box 89)
    - 1984, 2 folders (Box 89)
    - 1985 (Box 89)
    - 1986, 3 folders (Box 89)
    - 1987, 2 folders (Box 89)
    - 1988 (Box 89)
    - 1991, 3 folders (Box 89)
    - 1992 (Box 90)
    - 1998 (Box 90)
    - 2000, 2 folders (Box 90)
    - 2002 (Box 90)
    - 2003, 6 folders (Box 90)
    - 2003, 10 folders (Box 91)
    - 2003, 10 folders (Box 92)
    - 2003, 3 folders (Box 93)
    - 2004, 3 folders (Box 93)
    - 2005, 4 folders (Box 93)
    - 2005, 7 folders (Box 94)
    - 2005, 6 folders (Box 95)
    - 2006, 2 folders (Box 95)
    - 2006, 9 folders (Box 96)
    - 2006, 8 folders (Box 97)
    - 2006, 3 folders (Box 98)
    - 2007, 7 folders (Box 99)
    - 2008, 3 folders (Box 99)
    - 2008, 9 folders (Box 100)
    - 2008, 3 folders (Box 101)
    - 2009, 6 folders (Box 101)
    - 2009, 9 folders (Box 102)
    - 2009, 3 folders (Box 103)
  - Lexis Nexis searches, 6 folders (Box 103)
  - Lexis Nexis searches, 4 folders (Box 104)
  - Program shorts transcripts for 2003, 4 folders (Box 104)
  - Reader permissions, 4 folders (Box 104)
  - Reader permissions (Box 105)
  - Research files, Safire's original folder titles were retained.
    - 125th (Box 105)
    - 2000 AD (Box 105)
    - 2008-ese, 2 folders (Box 105)
    - 800 pound gorilla (Box 105)
    - 88 - heil Hitler (Box 105)
    - '88 watch (Box 105)
    - 9-w (Box 105)
    - 9/11 (Box 105)
    - A charge to keep (Box 105)
    - A couple experts (Box 105)
    - A-list (Box 105)
    - AAA (Box 105)
    - Abbreviations (Box 105)
    - Abolition/abolishment (Box 105)
    - About (Box 105)
    - Abrogate (Box 105)
    - Absquatulation (Box 105)
    - Academese, 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Ack-Ack (Box 105)
    - Acoustic (Box 105)
    - Acronymania (Box 105)
    - Acronyms, 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Actionable, 2 folders (Box 106)
    - Ad Lingo (Box 106)
    - Addresses (Box 106)
    - Adjectival endings (Box 106)
    - Adultery (Box 106)
    - Adverbs (Box 106)
    - Advertising, 2 folders (Box 106)
    - Affect v effect (Box 106)
    - Affinities (Box 106)
    - Afghanistan - Obama (Box 106)
    - Age and experience - internet terms (Box 106)
    - Age appropriate (Box 106)
    - Age defying (Box 106)
    - Aggie awards (Box 106)
    - Aggregate (Box 106)
    - Agita (Box 106)
    - Agon/agony, irrupt/erupt (Box 106)
    - Aha (Box 106)
    - Aid (Box 106)
    - Air tie (Box 106)
    - Airline-ese, 3 folders (Box 106)
    - AKA Abu, 4 folders (Box 106)
    - Akimbo (Box 106)
    - Akimbo (Box 106)
    - Al al qaeda (Box 106)
    - Al qaeda (Box 106)
    - Albeit (Box 106)
    - All courant (Box 107)
    - All downhill (Box 107)
    - All politics is local (Box 107)
    - All right (Box 107)
    - All the time (Box 107)
    - All told (Box 107)
    - Alleged (Box 107)
    - Alley oop, 2 folders (Box 107)
    - Allies v Coalition (Box 107)
    - Alliteration, 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Allocute (Box 107)
    - Almight Dollar, 4 folders (Box 107)
    - Alphonse - Gaston (Box 107)
    - Alternative(s) (Box 107)
    - Alzheimer's (Box 107)
    - Ambiguity (Box 107)
    - Ambiguous v Ambilvalent (Box 107)
    - American Dialect Society (ADS) (Box 107)
    - American Hospital Association (AHA) Terminology (Box 107)
    - Amerika (Box 107)
    - Amplifications of Aha (Box 107)
    - Anachronisms, 4 folders (Box 107)
    - Analogy (Box 108)
    - Angelism (Box 108)
    - Anglo (Box 108)
    - Angry white men/males (Box 108)
    - Angst about angstrom (Box 108)
    - Anhedonia (Box 108)
    - Animal spirits, 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Animal verbs (Box 108)
    - Animal warfare (Box 108)
    - Animals (Box 108)
    - Ankle biters (Box 108)
    - Ankled, 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Announcements (Box 108)
    - Annual report-ese (Box 108)
    - Annus horibilis, 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Anomalies, irregularities, mischief, 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Anomaly team (Box 108)
    - Anorak (Box 108)
    - Antifreeze - coolant (Box 108)
    - Anxious v eager (Box 108)
    - Any (Box 108)
    - Any more/anymore (Box 108)
    - AP style book (Box 108)
    - Apocalypse (Box 108)
    - Apocrypha(l), 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Apostrophes, 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Applause (Box 108)
    - Apples (Box 108)
    - Approve this message (Box 108)
    - Aptronyms (Box 108)
    - Arabians (Box 108)
    - Arabic e-mails (Box 108)
    - Arabic into English (Box 108)
    - Architecture (Box 109)
    - Are you thinking what we're thinking? (Box 109)
    - Aren't (Box 109)
    - -arians (Box 109)
    - Ariel salient (Box 109)
    - Armageddon, 2 folders (Box 109)
    - Arms (Box 109)
    - Arms control (Box 109)
    - Arrant nonsense - wedded words (Box 109)
    - As far as/so far as (Box 109)
    - As if! (Box 109)
    - As...as, so...as (Box 109)
    - Asian contagion (Box 109)
    - Asian words (Box 109)
    - Aspersion(s) (Box 109)
    - Associate (Box 109)
    - Assure/ensure/insure (endorse/indorse) (Box 109)
    - At (@), 3 folders (Box 109)
    - At the pleasure of the president, 2 folders (Box 109)
    - At you beckon call (Box 109)
    - Atmospherics (Box 109)
    - Atop (Box 109)
    - Atrium (Box 109)
    - Attaboy, attosecond, 3 folders (Box 109)
    - Attack dog (Box 109)
    - Attack video (Box 109)
    - Attest (Box 109)
    - Attributive noun phrases (Box 109)
    - Attributives (Box 110)
    - Auden, W.H. (Box 110)
    - Auger v Augur, 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Aung San Suu Ki (Box 110)
    - Australian (Box 110)
    - Automated v automatic (ergo v therefore), 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Autos (Box 110)
    - Avatar (Box 110)
    - Avulsive (Box 110)
    - Azeris (Box 110)
    - Baby boom (Box 110)
    - Back and fill (Box 110)
    - Back door/backdoor (Box 110)
    - Back story (Box 110)
    - Back-formation (Box 110)
    - Backmasking (Box 110)
    - Backronym (Box 110)
    - Backup (Box 110)
    - Bad guy (Box 110)
    - Bad/badly (Box 110)
    - Bagels - croissants (Box 110)
    - Baggage (Box 110)
    - Bags of... (Box 110)
    - Bait and switch (Box 110)
    - Ballistic missile (Box 110)
    - Balloon going up? (Box 110)
    - Ballotins (Box 110)
    - Balsamic (Box 110)
    - Barack (Box 110)
    - Barbarity/barbarism (Box 111)
    - Barnburners (Box 111)
    - Barnyard epithet (bullshit) (Box 111)
    - Baseball, 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Baseball nicknames (Box 111)
    - Bashing (Box 111)
    - Bastard nation (Box 111)
    - Battleground/swing/toss-up states (Box 111)
    - BC/BCE (Box 111)
    - Beaner - slurs (Box 111)
    - Beauty part (Box 111)
    - Because/since (Box 111)
    - Begs the question (Box 111)
    - Behalf (Box 111)
    - Behind the green door (Box 111)
    - Belgium's language war (Box 111)
    - Belly-up (Box 111)
    - Belts (Box 111)
    - Bemuse - mean formations (Box 111)
    - Benchmark(s)/timetable(s) (Box 112)
    - Benefit of clergy (Box 112)
    - Benign neglect (Box 112)
    - Bennies (Box 112)
    - Bent (Box 112)
    - Best practices (Box 112)
    - Better than/more than (Box 112)
    - Between the cracks/stools (Box 112)
    - Between/among (Box 112)
    - Beyond the pale (Box 112)
    - Biblical chiasmus (Box 112)
    - Bicenquinquagenary (Box 112)
    - Big apple controversy (Box 112)
    - Big picture (Box 112)
    - Big words (Box 112)
    - Bilge (Box 112)
    - Bilingual education (Box 112)
    - Bilingualism (Box 112)
    - Billion(s) - large numbers (Box 112)
    - Bimbo (Box 112)
    - Bin laden, Osama - translation of tapes (Box 112)
    - Bioethics (Box 112)
    - Bird-dog minute (Box 112)
    - Bit/bitten (Box 113)
    - Bitch (Box 113)
    - "Bite" - economics (Box 113)
    - Bits (Box 113)
    - Bitter (Box 113)
    - Black (Box 113)
    - Black dog publisher (Box 113)
    - Black English (Box 113)
    - Black hand (Box 113)
    - Black holes (Box 113)
    - Blame game (Box 113)
    - Blame on/blame for (Box 113)
    - Blandander (Box 113)
    - Blargon (Box 113)
    - Blasphemy (Box 113)
    - Blended compounds (Box 113)
    - Blind tiger (Box 113)
    - Blob (Box 113)
    - Blog (Box 113)
    - Blog/Newspaper jargon (Box 113)
    - Bloomberg, Michael - I did it my ways (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - 1995/1996 (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - 2000 (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - 2006/2007 (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - 2007 (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - 2008 (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - undated (Box 113)
    - Bloopies - undated, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Blowing smoke (Box 114)
    - Blowtorch (Box 114)
    - Blue dog democrat (Box 114)
    - Blue on blue (Box 114)
    - Blurb-ese (Box 114)
    - Bodega (Box 114)
    - Bodes well (Box 114)
    - Body candy - Arm candy, ear candy, eye candy, mind candy, nose candy (Box 114)
    - Body parts (Box 114)
    - Body wash (Box 114)
    - Boeing 727 (Box 114)
    - Bogey (Box 114)
    - Bogey man (Box 114)
    - Bogsat (Box 114)
    - Bogus titles (Box 114)
    - Boilerplat (Box 114)
    - Boldface names (Box 114)
    - Boldface(d) (Box 114)
    - Boldface(d)/baldface(d) (Box 115)
    - Boll weevil (Box 115)
    - Bombay/Mumbai (Box 115)
    - Bomfog (Box 115)
    - Bon mots (Box 115)
    - Boots on the ground (Box 115)
    - Bop (Box 115)
    - Botanical garden (Box 115)
    - Bought and paid for (Box 115)
    - Bought the farm (Box 115)
    - Boxing phrases (Box 115)
    - Boys (Box 115)
    - Bozo (Box 115)
    - Bradley effect - Bradley, Tom (Box 115)
    - Bradley, Bill (Box 115)
    - Brand (Box 115)
    - Brand names (Box 115)
    - Brand-new/Bran-new (Box 115)
    - Brat (Box 115)
    - Bread line (Box 115)
    - Break a leg (Box 115)
    - Breakbasket (Box 115)
    - Breakout (Box 115)
    - Breeches (Box 115)
    - Bridge to nowhere (Box 115)
    - Bring it on! (Box 115)
    - Bring v take (Box 115)
    - British english (Box 115)
    - British monarchy (Box 115)
    - Britishism (Box 115)
    - Broad (Box 115)
    - Bronx, the (Box 116)
    - Brown bagging (Box 116)
    - Bubbe hypothesis (Box 116)
    - Bubble (Box 116)
    - Bum's rush (Box 116)
    - Bummel (Box 116)
    - Bump - baby's age (Box 116)
    - Bumper (Box 116)
    - Bundle, 2 folders (Box 116)
    - Bungie (Box 116)
    - Bunker mentality (Box 116)
    - Bunny hop - limboed (Box 116)
    - Burchfield, Robert (Box 116)
    - Bureaucrat-ese (Box 116)
    - Burma shave - road signs (Box 116)
    - Bushisms (Box 116)
    - Bushspeak (Box 116)
    - Business-ese (Box 116)
    - Busking - ligging (Box 116)
    - Bust (Box 116)
    - Busywork (Box 116)
    - Butter wouldn't melt in her mouth (Box 116)
    - Butterfly wings (Box 116)
    - Butters, Ron (Box 116)
    - Buzz (Box 116)
    - Bye (Box 117)
    - Cable-ese (Box 117)
    - Cache/cachet (Box 117)
    - Caesarean (Box 117)
    - Cake walk (Box 117)
    - Calculus (Box 117)
    - Californiacs (Box 117)
    - Calumny (Box 117)
    - Campaign oratory (Box 117)
    - Campaign salutations (Box 117)
    - Canard (Box 117)
    - Candid v honest (Box 117)
    - Cannon (Box 117)
    - Cannot help but/can't help but (Box 117)
    - Cantor/hazan/khazeray (Box 117)
    - Canucks (Box 117)
    - Capitalization (Box 117)
    - Capitulate/surrender - articles of capitulation, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Card sharp (Box 117)
    - Carlin, George (Box 117)
    - Carp (Box 117)
    - Carpetbagger (Box 117)
    - Cartels (Box 117)
    - Cartoons (Box 117)
    - Cat and mouse (Box 117)
    - Catalogue-ese, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Catbird seat (Box 118)
    - Catch phrase (Box 118)
    - Catch the falling knife - cook the books - tank (Box 118)
    - Catch-as-catch-can (Box 118)
    - Categorical (Box 118)
    - Catharsis (Box 118)
    - Catsup/ketchup (Box 118)
    - Cattle show (Box 118)
    - Caucus (Box 118)
    - Cause célèbre (Box 118)
    - Causistics (Box 118)
    - CC (Box 118)
    - Celebrity name conflations (Box 118)
    - Celluluddites (Box 118)
    - Censure (Box 118)
    - Centennial/centenary (Box 118)
    - Centeritis (Box 118)
    - Centre/center (Box 118)
    - Change agent (Box 118)
    - Channel (Box 118)
    - Charley horse (Box 118)
    - Chat up (Box 118)
    - Chav (Box 118)
    - Cheap shot (Box 118)
    - Checkist (Box 118)
    - Chef v cook (Box 118)
    - Cheney, Dick - Doctor Quotations (Box 118)
    - Cherry picking (Box 119)
    - Chess - gambit v play (Box 119)
    - Chess metaphors (Box 119)
    - Chesterfield, Lord (Box 119)
    - Chiasmus (Box 119)
    - Chicken D's (Box 119)
    - Chinese (Box 119)
    - Chinky chose (Box 119)
    - Chiphead, -head (Box 119)
    - Choice v necessity (Box 119)
    - Choices - proverbial (Box 119)
    - Chomsky, Noam (Box 119)
    - Chop-chop (Box 119)
    - Chopsticks (Box 119)
    - Christmas card lingo (Box 119)
    - Chutzpah (Box 119)
    - Chyron (Box 119)
    - -cide (Box 119)
    - Cigar (Box 119)
    - Cinnabar as syphilis treatment (Box 119)
    - -cion (Box 119)
    - -cis (Box 119)
    - Citizen journalist, 2 folders (Box 119)
    - Civil unions (Box 119)
    - Civil war v sectarian violence (Box 119)
    - Claim responsibility (Box 119)
    - Clank (Box 119)
    - Class struggle (Box 119)
    - Class warfare (Box 119)
    - Classic (Box 120)
    - Clay pigeon amendment (Box 120)
    - Clean house (Box 120)
    - Clean your clock (Box 120)
    - Cleavage (Box 120)
    - Clergy - rabbi (Box 120)
    - Clichés (Box 120)
    - Climate change (Box 120)
    - Clinton-isms (Box 120)
    - Clinton, Bill - second inaugural (Box 120)
    - Close enough for government work (Box 120)
    - Closer (Box 120)
    - Clothes of Watergate (Box 120)
    - Clothespin vote (Box 120)
    - Clunkers (Box 120)
    - Co-equal (Box 120)
    - Cock and Bull (Box 120)
    - Cohesive (Box 120)
    - Coinages (Box 120)
    - Coincidently [sic] (Box 120)
    - Coined by Shakespeare (Box 120)
    - Cold War II (Box 121)
    - Cold-pressed olive oil (Box 121)
    - Collaborative v operational, 2 folders (Box 121)
    - Collective nouns (Box 121)
    - College slang, 2 folders (Box 121)
    - Collywobble (Box 121)
    - Column ideas (Box 121)
    - Come a cropper (Box 121)
    - Comfort food (Box 121)
    - Comfort level (Box 121)
    - Comfortable (Box 121)
    - Comics (Box 121)
    - Comma (Box 121)
    - Communist lingo (Box 121)
    - Commutershed (Box 121)
    - Company names (Box 121)
    - Comparable worth (Box 121)
    - Comparatives (Box 122)
    - Compound adjectives (Box 122)
    - Comprise(s)/compose(d) (Box 122)
    - Computer byte (Box 122)
    - Computer-ese, 4 folders (Box 122)
    - Concern (Box 122)
    - Conclusory (Box 122)
    - Confabular (Box 122)
    - Congress (Box 122)
    - Consensus of opinion (Box 122)
    - Consent of the governed (Box 122)
    - Contingent force (Box 122)
    - Contrarian (Box 122)
    - Contumely (Box 122)
    - Conundrum-beat (Box 122)
    - Conventional v traditional v historical (Box 122)
    - Convince v persuade (Box 122)
    - Cook goose (Box 122)
    - Cook the books/off the books (Box 122)
    - Cooke, Alistair, 2 folders (Box 123)
    - Cookie (Box 123)
    - Cooking (Box 123)
    - Cool (Box 123)
    - Coon (Box 123)
    - Cooper Institute (Box 123)
    - Core group (Box 123)
    - Corp names (Box 123)
    - Corrections, 2 folders (Box 123)
    - Cosmetic-ese (Box 123)
    - Cottage industry (Box 123)
    - Cotton to (Box 123)
    - Countrypeople (Box 123)
    - Coup de main (Box 123)
    - Cover/cover band (Box 123)
    - Covert v clandestine (Box 123)
    - Cowabunga (Box 123)
    - Cowboy (Box 123)
    - Cq (Box 124)
    - Cram v shovel (Box 124)
    - Crash and burn (Box 124)
    - Crawfish (Box 124)
    - Crazy terms (Box 124)
    - Credit crunch (Box 124)
    - Crescendo (Box 124)
    - Criminal lingo (Box 124)
    - Critical infrastructure (Box 124)
    - Critique/criticism (Box 124)
    - Crossword puzzles (Box 124)
    - Crowding out (Box 124)
    - Crowdsourcing (Box 124)
    - Cuckold (Box 124)
    - Cue language, 2 folders (Box 124)
    - Culpa for mea (Box 124)
    - Cultivational (Box 124)
    - Customize (Box 124)
    - Cut a check (Box 124)
    - Cut a deal (Box 124)
    - Cut and run, 2 folders (Box 124)
    - Cut him some slack (Box 124)
    - Cutout (Box 124)
    - Cutsmanship (Box 124)
    - Cutting edge (Box 125)
    - Cyber- (Box 125)
    - Cygnet (Box 125)
    - Da Vinci Code, The (Box 125)
    - Daisy chain (Box 125)
    - Daisy cutter (Box 125)
    - Damned if you do (Box 125)
    - Dance (Box 125)
    - Dangling modifier (Box 125)
    - Dangling participle (Box 125)
    - Database (Box 125)
    - Day one (Box 125)
    - De Tocqueville, Alexis (Box 125)
    - Dead cat bounce (Box 125)
    - Dead end (Box 125)
    - Dead enders (Box 125)
    - Dead heat (Box 125)
    - Dead or alive (Box 125)
    - Dead ringer (Box 125)
    - Deal breaker (Box 125)
    - Dear (Box 125)
    - Dear - salutation (Box 125)
    - Dear leader (Box 125)
    - Death penalty - eligibility (Box 125)
    - Death worthy (Box 125)
    - Debacle (Box 126)
    - Decapitate (Box 126)
    - Deceipt (Box 126)
    - Deconstruct v Analyze (Box 126)
    - Decremental (Box 126)
    - Deep-penetrating/deeply penetrating (Box 126)
    - Defalcation (Box 126)
    - Default outfit (Box 126)
    - DEFCON two (Box 126)
    - Defenestration (Box 126)
    - Defense-ese (Box 126)
    - Defining moment (Box 126)
    - Deflation (Box 126)
    - Deliberate mispelling (Box 126)
    - Demerge (Box 126)
    - Democrat party (Box 126)
    - Democratic friends (Box 126)
    - Denounce v reject (Box 126)
    - Denturism (Box 126)
    - Derivatives (Box 126)
    - Derogging (Box 126)
    - Derring-do (Box 126)
    - Desecration (Box 126)
    - Design Issue (Box 126)
    - Despicable - pronunciation (Box 126)
    - Detente (Box 126)
    - Determine (Box 126)
    - Dialect differences (Box 126)
    - Dibs (Box 126)
    - Dicey (Box 126)
    - Dictionaries (Box 126)
    - Dictionary of American Regional English - Hall, Joan (Box 126)
    - Dictionary of American Regional English - Hall, Joan (Box 127)
    - Dictionary of American Regional English, 2 folders (Box 127)
    - Dictionary of Historical Slang (Box 127)
    - Dictionary of Troublesome English - Bryson, Bill (Box 127)
    - Dictionary Society of North America (Box 127)
    - Diffident (Box 127)
    - Digitese (Box 127)
    - Digitize (Box 127)
    - Digitize - film (Box 127)
    - Dike/dyke (Box 127)
    - Diminutive first names - senators (Box 127)
    - Dingbats (Box 127)
    - Diplolingo (Box 127)
    - Diplomat-ese (Box 127)
    - Directions (Box 127)
    - Dirigisme (Box 127)
    - Dirty dozen (Box 127)
    - Dirty tricks (Box 127)
    - Disabled (Box 127)
    - Disappearing words (Box 127)
    - Disarm v dismantle (Box 127)
    - Disconnect (Box 127)
    - Disgust - words of disgust (Box 127)
    - Dish (Box 128)
    - Disinformation (Box 128)
    - Dissociate/disassociate (Box 128)
    - Distraction (Box 128)
    - Dither (Box 128)
    - Diva, 2 folders (Box 128)
    - Do (Box 128)
    - Do believe (Box 128)
    - Do the right thing (Box 128)
    - Doable/do-able (Box 128)
    - Doctoring (Box 128)
    - Doctrinaire (Box 128)
    - Doctrine, 2 folders (Box 128)
    - Dog - expressions (Box 128)
    - Dog ate my homework (Box 128)
    - Dog didn't bark (Box 128)
    - Dog-whistle politics (Box 128)
    - Dominate/dominance (Box 128)
    - Dominatrix (Box 128)